American Painting Section of the Mounted Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
American Painting Section of the Mounted Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 1
Yale University Arts Library
64
152 boxes
Consists of reproductive photographs of original paintings from a variety of countries, cultures, time periods and in a variety of styles.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The photographs in the collection were acquired, over a sixty year period, from a diversearray of sources, including newspapers, magazines, auction catalogs, books, galleryannouncements, calendars, postcards, and as gifts or purchases.
Conditions Governing Access
Anyone can use the photograph collection for reference purposes, but only members of theYale University community can check out the photographs, on a temporary basis, for thepurpose of research and study for Yale University courses.
Biographical / Historical
The photograph collection was begun in the 1930's, by the Yale University School of FineArts, for the purpose of teaching and study. Subsequently, in 1952, the photograph collectionbecame a part of the Art and Architecture Library where it progressively grew, and also,continued to be utilized as a reference, research, and instructional tool by faculty and students.At the present time, the photograph collection is primarily used as a resource of images forphoto study by students for History of Art and related courses, but the collection is also stillused, albeit on a less frequent level, for reference and research purposes. As a result of boththe proliferation of a collection of digitized images, and the need to economize space in thepending construction of a new Arts Library; in 1999, it was proposed that the photographcollection be relocated as an archival collection to the University's off-site Library ShelvingFacility, and that a finding aid be created to provide efficient access to the materials within thecollection.
Scope and Contents
The photograph collection consists of approximately 195,000 mounted black and white,and color, photographic reproductions of original works significant to the realms of the historyof art and the history of architecture. The collection embraces both Western and non-Westerncultures, and furthermore, encompasses time periods stretching from prehistoric times to thepresent. The collection is multidimensional in nature incorporating Architecture, Painting,Sculpture and the Minor Arts. Drawing is also represented within the collection. A large groupof folders containing miscellaneous clippings are dispersed throughout the collection, and theyaccompany related sections and photographs within the collection. Three different sizephotographs comprise the collection - small (which comprises the bulk of the collection),medium and large. Furthermore, the collection also includes a group of photographs referred toas white mounts, which are merely photographs of varied sizes mounted on white mat board.
Series II: Painting consists of reproductive photographs of original paintings from a varietyof countries, cultures, time periods and in a variety of styles. Photographs of drawings are alsoincluded, and are interfiled with those of paintings; however, if there were a large quantity ofdrawings for a particular artist, a separate section was made in that artist's hierarchy fordrawings. Folders containing miscellaneous clippings are filed with related sections in thecollection.
Arrangement
Painting is arranged alphabetically by country, and alphabetically by artist therein. desctiption fo all four sectionsSeries I: Architecture
Arrangement
The sub-series, United States, is divided into two major sections: Anonymous and Miscellaneous & Individual Artists.
The Anonymous section is arranged chronologicallyl by century, and by genre therein. The20th Century Anonymous subseries is divided into a general section, and then a genre section.
The Miscellaneous & Individual Artists section is arrangedalphabetically. Within each letter of the alphabet there is a Miscellaneous Artists section,followed by an Individual Artists section. The Miscellaneous Artists sections are divided intoalphabetic ranges. The Individual Artists sections are arranged alphabetically by artist. Withineach artist's division the arrangement is usually by location or chronology, but occasionally by genre if the artist was prolific. Photographs of drawings by artists are interfiled with their paintings, unless there are a substantial amount of drawings, in which case a separate section is incorporated within that particular artist'shierarchy.
Painting, American; Photographs; Reproductions
- Anonymous (Box 1)
  - XVII Century., 13 (Box 1)
    - Genres (Box 1)
      - Portraits, Female, 6 (Box 1)
      - Portraits, Male, 7 (Box 1)
  - XVIII Century., 42 (Box 1)
    - Genres (Box 1)
      - Landscapes, 3 (Box 1)
      - Portraits, Children, 5 (Box 1)
      - Portraits, Female, 12 (Box 1)
      - Portraits, Male, 19 (Box 1)
      - Portraits, Pendant Pieces, 2 (Box 1)
      - Religious Paintings, 4 (Box 1)
  - XIX Century., 138 (Box 1–2)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Genres (Box 2)
      - Allegory, 5 (Box 2)
      - Animal Paintings, 3 (Box 2)
      - Folk Art, 3 (Box 2)
      - Genre Scenes, 24 (Box 2)
      - History Painting/Historical Scenes, 4 (Box 2–3)
      - Landscapes, 31 (Box 3)
      - Portraits, Children, 14 (Box 3)
      - Portraits, Female, 7 (Box 3)
      - Portraits, Group, 5 (Box 3–4)
      - Portraits, Male, 18 (Box 4)
      - Portraits, Miniatures, 4 (Box 4)
      - Religious Paintings, 6 (Box 4)
      - Seascapes, 4 (Box 4)
      - Still-Lifes, 10 (Box 4)
  - XX Century., 5 (Box 4–5)
    Includes 4 folders of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Documentary Materials, 3 (Box 5)
    - Mural Paintings, 2 (Box 5)
- A (Box 5)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "A" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ab-Al., 18 (Box 5)
    - Abercrombie, Gertrude, 1909-1977., 1 (Box 5)
    - Abrams, Isaac, 20th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Adams, Charles Partridge, 19th c?., 1 (Box 5)
    - Adams, John Quincy, ?-1933., 2 (Box 5)
    - Adams, Pat, 20th c., 3 (Box 5)
    - Adomeit, George, 1879-?., 2 (Box 5)
    - Agostini, Peter, 20th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Albert,Calvin, 20th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Albro, Maxine, 1903-., 2 (Box 5)
    - Alexander, Cosmo John, c.1724-1772., 1 (Box 5)
    - Alexander, Francis, 1800-1880., 2 (Box 5)
    - Alden, James Madison, ac. 1854-1860., 1 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Am-Ar., 20 (Box 5)
    - Ames, Ezra, 1768-1836., 1 (Box 5)
    - Ames, Joseph Alexander, 1816-1872., 1 (Box 5)
    - Amezcua, Consuelo Gonzalez, 20th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Anderson, Guy, 1907-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Anderson, John, 1927-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Andrade, Edna, 1917-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Andre, Carl, 1935-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Angus, Patrick, 1953-1992., 1 (Box 5)
    - Anthony, William, 1934-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Appleman, Boni, 1910-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Appleman, Dale, 1945-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Arledge, Sara-Kathryn, 20th c., 2 (Box 5)
    - Armajani, Siah, 20th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Armfield, Maxwell, 1862-?., 1 (Box 5)
    - Arnautoff, Victor, 20th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Arnold, Anne, 1925-?., 1 (Box 5)
    - Arnold, E., 19th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Aronson, David, 1923-?., 1 (Box 5)
    - Artschwager, Richard, 1924-?., 1 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: As-Av., 12 (Box 5)
    - Ashbaugh, Dennis, 1946-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Ashley, Clifford W, 1881-., 2 (Box 5)
    - Attie, Dotty, 20th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Augustin, Fernandez, 20th c., 1 (Box 5)
    - Austin, Darrel, 1907-?., 2 (Box 5)
    - Austin, Howard B., 19th c?., 3 (Box 5)
    - Avedisian, Howard, 1936-., 2 (Box 5)
  - Individual Artists (Box 5–6)
    - Abbey, Edwin Austin, 1852-1911., 60 (Box 6)
      - Drawings, 23 (Box 6)
      - Location Unknown, 4 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 5 (Box 6)
      - New Haven, 28 (Box 6)
    - Adams, Wayman, 1883-1959., 3 (Box 6)
    - Albers, Josef, 1888-1976., total of 32 photographs. (Box 6)
      - Before 1940, 10 (Box 7)
      - 1940's-1960's, 22 (Box 7)
    - Albright, Ivan, 1897-., 8 (Box 7)
    - Alexander, John W., 1856-1915., 8 (Box 7)
    - Allston, Washington, 1779-1843., total of 51 photographs. (Box 7)
      - Private Collection, 2 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 17 (Box 7)
      - Boston, 12 (Box 8)
      - Cambridge, 9 (Box 8)
      - Detroit, 11 (Box 8)
    - Anshutz, Thomas, 1851-1912., 5 (Box 8)
    - Anuszkiewicz, Richard Joseph, 1930-., 9 (Box 8)
    - Atherton, John, 1900-1952., 4 (Box 8)
    - Audubon, John James, 1785-1851., 14 (Box 8)
    - Ault, George, 1891-1948., 5 (Box 8)
    - Avery, Milton, 1885-1965., 24 (Box 9)
- B (Box 9)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "B" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ba., 20 (Box 9)
    - Bacher, Otto, 1856-1909., 1 (Box 9)
    - Bacon, Linda, 1942-., 1 (Box 9)
    - Bacon, Peggy, 1895-?., 3 (Box 9)
    - Baeder, John, 1938-., 2 (Box 9)
    - Baldessari, John, 1931-., 1 (Box 9)
    - Baldwin, C. or E., 20th c., 1 (Box 9)
    - Ballantyne, Dale, 20th c., 1 (Box 9)
    - Bannard, Walter Darby, 1937-., 1 (Box 9)
    - Bannister, Edward Mitchell, 1825-1901., 3 (Box 9)
    - Barber, John, 1893-1965., 1 (Box 9)
    - Barnes, Charles, 1915-?., 1 (Box 9)
    - Barnes, Lucius, 19th c., 1 (Box 9)
    - Barnes, Matthew, 1880-?., 1 (Box 9)
    - Barringer, Maria, 19th c., 1 (Box 9)
    - Bauermeister, Mary, 1934-., 1 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Bea-Bec., 13 (Box 9–10)
    - Beal, Reynolds, 1867-1946., 3 (Box 10)
    - Beard, William Holbrook, 1824-1900., 1 (Box 10)
    - Beauchamp, Robert, 1923-?., 4 (Box 10)
    - Bechtle, Robert, 1932-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Becker, J., 1841-1910., 1 (Box 10)
    - Beckman, William, 1942-., 3 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Bed-Bez., 26 (Box 10)
    - Belknap, Irene, 1941-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Belknap, Zedekiah, 1781-1858., 2 (Box 10)
    - Bell, Charles, 1935-., 4 (Box 10)
    - Bell, Leland, 20th c., 3 (Box 10)
    - Bemelmans, Ludwig, 20th c., 2 (Box 10)
    - Benbridge, Henry, 1744-1812., 2 (Box 10)
    - Benedetto, Angelo di, 1915-?., 2 (Box 10)
    - Beneker, Gerret, 1882-1934., 2 (Box 10)
    - Bengston, Billy Al, 1934-., 2 (Box 10)
    - Benn, Ben., 1 (Box 10)
    - Benson, Eugene, 1839-1908., 1 (Box 10)
    - Beny, Wilfred, 20th c., 1 (Box 10)
    - Berkowitz, Leon, 1919-?., 2 (Box 10)
    - Berthot, Jake, 1939-., 1 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Bi-Bla., 23 (Box 10)
    - Biala, Janice, 20th c., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bigelow, Olive, 20th c., 3 (Box 10)
    - Biggers, John, 1924-?., 2 (Box 10)
    - Billings, Henry, 1901-?., 1 (Box 10)
    - Birren, Joseph, 20th c., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bischoff, Elmer, 1916-?., 4 (Box 10)
    - Bishop, James, 20th c., 1 (Box 10)
    - Blaine, Nell, 1922-?., 4 (Box 10)
    - Blakewell, Robert, 19th c., 1 (Box 10)
    - Blanch, Arnold, 1896-?., 2 (Box 10)
    - Blanchard, James, 19th c., 1 (Box 10)
    - Blaney, Dwight, 1865-?., 1 (Box 10)
    - Blackwell, Tom, 20th c., 1 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Blo-Bly., 14 (Box 10)
    - Bloch, Albert, 1882-?., 4 (Box 10)
    - Bluhm, Norman, 1921-?., 2 (Box 10)
    - Blum, Jerome, 1884-?., 1 (Box 10)
    - Blumenschein, Ernest, 1874-?., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bluemner, Oscar, 1867-1938., 3 (Box 10)
    - Blunt, Joseph S., 19th c., 1 (Box 10)
    - Blyth, Benjamin, 1746-1787., 2 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Bo., 21 (Box 10–11)
    - Bodmer, Charles, 1809-1893., 3 (Box 11)
    - Boggs, Frank Meyers, 1855-1926., 3 (Box 11)
    - Bohm, Max, 1868-1923., 2 (Box 11)
    - Bontecou, Lee, 1931-., 2 (Box 11)
    - Booth, Cameron, 1892-?., 1 (Box 11)
    - Borg, Carl Oscar, 1879-?., 1 (Box 11)
    - Bosman, Richard, 1944-., 3 (Box 11)
    - Botke, Jessie Arms, 1883-?., 1 (Box 11)
    - Botts, John, 1933-., 1 (Box 11)
    - Boutelle, Dewitt Clinton, 1820-1889., 1 (Box 11)
    - Bower, Gary, 20th c., 1 (Box 11)
    - Boyle, Ferdinand, 1820-1906., 1 (Box 11)
    - Boza, Daniel, 20th c., 1 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Bra-Bri., 30 (Box 11)
    - Brackman, Robert, 1896-?., 3 (Box 11)
    - Bradley, Mary, 19th c., 1 (Box 11)
    - Bradley, I., 19th c., 1 (Box 11)
    - Brady, Carolyn, 1937-., 2 (Box 11)
    - Brady, Matthew, 19th c., 1 (Box 11)
    - Brainard, Joe, 1942-., 4 (Box 11)
    - Brandt, Warren, 20th c., 1 (Box 11)
    - Brandt, Sharon, 20th c., 1 (Box 11)
    - Braun, Maurice, 1877-?, 2 (Box 11)
    - Brauner, Olaf, 1869-?., 1 (Box 11)
    - Brauntuch, Troy, 20th c., 1 (Box 11)
    - Bravo, Claudio, 1936-., 2 (Box 11)
    - Bredin, R. Sloan, 1881-1933., 2 (Box 11)
    - Breinin, Raymond, 1909-?., 2 (Box 11)
    - Brewster, John Jr., 1766-1854., 4 (Box 11)
    - Bricher, Alfred T., 1837-1908., 1 (Box 11)
    - Briggs, Ernest, 1923-?., 1 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Bro-Bru., 33 (Box 11)
    - Broderson, Morris, 1928-?., 3 (Box 11)
    - Brodie, Gandy, 1924-1976., 1 (Box 11)
    - Broemel, Carl, 1891-?., 3 (Box 11)
    - Brooks, Arthur D., 1877-?., 2 (Box 11)
    - Brooks, Romaine C., 1874-1970., 4 (Box 11)
    - Brown, Appleton, 1844-1902., 1 (Box 11)
    - Brown, Douglas, 1904-?., 2 (Box 11)
    - Brown, Grafton Tyler, 1841-1918., 1 (Box 11)
    - Brown, Joan, 1938-., 3 (Box 11)
    - Brown, Mather, 1761-1831., 3 (Box 11)
    - Brown, Roger, 1941-., 3 (Box 11)
    - Browne, Byron, 1907-?., 2 (Box 11)
    - Brownell, Charles DeWolff, 1822-1901., 2 (Box 11)
    - Broyles, Niki, 1947-., 1 (Box 11)
    - Brusca, Jack, 1939-., 1 (Box 11)
    - Brustlein, Daniel, 20th c., 1 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Bu., 25 (Box 11–12)
    - Buchr, Karl Albert, 1866-1952., 1 (Box 12)
    - Budd, David, 1927-?., 2 (Box 12)
    - Buller, Audrey, 1902-?., 2 (Box 12)
    - Bunn, William, 1910-?., 1 (Box 12)
    - Bunting, J.D., 19th c., 1 (Box 12)
    - Burgis, William, 18th c., 4 (Box 12)
    - Burlin, Paul, 1886-?., 2 (Box 12)
    - Burkhardt, Hans, 1904-?., 2 (Box 12)
    - Burko, Diane, 1945-., 1 (Box 12)
    - Burnham, Thomas M., 1818-1866., 1 (Box 12)
    - Butler, Theodore E., 1860-1936., 1 (Box 12)
    - Buttersworth, James Edward, 1817-?., 4 (Box 12)
    - Button, John, 1929-?., 3 (Box 12)
  - Individual Artists (Box 12)
    - Bacon, Emma, ?-1942., 3 (Box 12)
    - Badger, Joseph, 1708-1765., 34 (Box 12)
    - Bailey, William, 1930-., 14 (Box 13)
    - Bard, James, 1815-1897., 4 (Box 13)
    - Barnet, Will, 1911-., 6 (Box 13)
    - Bartlett, Jennifer, 1941-., 12 (Box 13)
    - Basquiat, Jean-Michel, 1960-1988., 15 (Box 13)
    - Baskerville, Charles, 20th C., 4 (Box 13)
    - Baskin, Leonard, 1922-., 5 (Box 13)
    - Baziotes, William, 1912-1963., 9 (Box 13)
    - Beal, Gifford, 1879-1956., 14 (Box 14)
    - Beal, Jack, 1931-., 8 (Box 14)
    - Bearden, Romare, 1914-1988., 16 (Box 14)
    - Beardsley Limner, 18th c., 3 (Box 14)
    - Beaux, Cecilia, 1855-1942., 9 (Box 14)
    - Bellows, George, 1882-1925., total of 67 photographs. (Box 14–15)
      - Location Unknown, 21 (Box 15)
      - Private Collection, 4 (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-B, 7 (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: C-L, 7 (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: M-Z, 19 (Box 15)
      - New Haven, 9 (Box 15)
    - Benson, Frank, 1862-1951., 13 (Box 16)
    - Benton, Thomas Hart, 1889-1975., total of 72 photographs. (Box 16)
      - Drawings, 8 (Box 16)
      - Location Unknown, 10 (Box 16)
      - Location Unknown, continued., 8 (Box 16)
      - Private Collection, 1 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 17 (Box 17)
      - New York, 6 (Box 17)
        - Individual Repositories, New York: School for Social Research, 16 (Box 17)
        - Individual Repositories, New York: Whitney Museum, 6 (Box 17)
    - Berman, Eugene, 1899-1972., 15 (Box 17)
    - Biddle, George, 1885-1973., 7 (Box 17)
    - Bierstadt, Albert, 1830-1902., total of 102 photographs. (Box 17–18)
      - Location Unknown, 6 (Box 18)
      - Private Collection, 8 (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous Cities, 49 (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous Cities, continued., 15 (Box 18)
      - Boston, 18 (Box 18)
      - Hartford, 6 (Box 18)
    - Bingham, George Caleb, 1811-1879., total of 45 photographs. (Box 18–19)
      - Location Unknown, 5 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-D, 11 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: E-Z, 13 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: E-Z, continued., 16 (Box 19)
    - Birch, Thomas, 1779-1851., 12 (Box 19)
    - Bishop, Isabel, 1902-1988., 8 (Box 19)
    - Blackburn, Joseph, c. 1700-1763., 16 (Box 20)
    - Blakelock, Ralph Albert, 1847-1919., 19 (Box 20)
    - Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1848-1936., 4 (Box 20)
    - Bloom, Hyman, 1913-., 4 (Box 20)
    - Blume, Peter, 1906-., total of 17 photographs. (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 5 (Box 20)
      - New York, 12 (Box 20)
    - Blythe, David Gilmour, 1815-1865., 14 (Box 21)
    - Bohrod, Aaron, 1907-., 8 (Box 21)
    - Bosa, Louis, 1906-., 3 (Box 21)
    - Bouche, Louis, 1896-1969., 3 (Box 21)
    - Bradford, Francis Scott, 1898-., 4 (Box 21)
    - Bridges, Charles, 1670-1747., 4 (Box 21)
    - Brook, Alexander, 1898-1980., 14 (Box 21)
    - Brooks, James, 1906-., 12 (Box 22)
      Includes exhibition catalog.
    - Brown, George Loring, 1814-1889., 6 (Box 22)
    - Brown, John George, 1831-1913., 7 (Box 22)
    - Bruce, Edward, 1879-1943., 3 (Box 22)
    - Bruce, Patrick Henry, 1881-1936., 6 (Box 22)
    - Brush, George de Forest, 1855-1941., 10 (Box 22)
    - Burchfield, Charles, 1893-1967., total of 47 photographs. (Box 22–23)
      - Location Unknown, 19 (Box 23)
      - Private Collection, 5 (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 9 (Box 23)
      - Cleveland, 6 (Box 23)
      - New York, 8 (Box 23)
- C (Box 23–24)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "C" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ca-Ce., 21 (Box 24)
    - Cajori, Charles, 20th c., 1 (Box 24)
    - Camblin, Bob, 20th c., 1 (Box 24)
    - Candee, George Edward, 1838-?., 1 (Box 24)
    - Canier, Caren, 1953-., 1 (Box 24)
    - Carlson, Cynthia, 1942-., 1 (Box 24)
    - Carmiencke, Johann Hermann, 1810-1867., 1 (Box 24)
    - Carnes, Vivian, 20th c., 1 (Box 24)
    - Carnwath, Squeak, 1947-., 1 (Box 24)
    - Carone, Nicholas, 20th c., 1 (Box 24)
    - Carpenter, Francis Bicknell, 1830-1900., 3 (Box 24)
    - Carter, Clarence Holbrook, 1904-?., 4 (Box 24)
    - Carter, Mrs. Robert, 19th c., 1 (Box 24)
    - Cary, William de la Montaigne, 1840-1922., 1 (Box 24)
    - Casilaer, John W, 1811-1893., 1 (Box 24)
    - Castellon, Federico, 20th c., 1 (Box 24)
    - Celmins, Vija, 1938-., 1 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Chae-Chas., 26 (Box 24)
    - Chaet, Bernard, 1924-?., 2 (Box 24)
    - Chalfant, Jefferson David, 1856-1931., 1 (Box 24)
    - Chamberlain, Sam E., 1829-1908., 2 (Box 24)
    - Champney, James, 1843-1905., 2 (Box 24)
    - Chandler, Winthrop, 1747-1790., 3 (Box 24)
    - Chaney, Stewart, 1910-1969., 2 (Box 24)
    - Chanler, Robert, 1872-1930., 1 (Box 24)
    - Chapin, Francis, 1899-?., 2 (Box 24)
    - Chapin, James, 20th c., 2 (Box 24)
    - Chapman, Conrad Wise, 19th c., 2 (Box 24)
    - Chapman, John G., 1808-1889., 3 (Box 24)
    - Chase, Louisa, 1951-., 1 (Box 24)
    - Chase-Riboud, Barbara, 1936-., 1 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Chi-Ci., 11 (Box 24)
    - Chicago, Judy, 1939-., 1 (Box 24)
    - Christensen, Dan, 1942-., 4 (Box 24)
    - Christy, Howard Chandler, 1873-1952., 1 (Box 24)
    - Church, Henry, 1836-1908., 3 (Box 24)
    - Cikovsky, Nicolai, 1894-?., 2 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Cl., 12 (Box 24–25)
    - Clark, Alan, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Clark, Walter Appleton, 1876-1906., 1 (Box 25)
    - Clarke, John Clem, 1937-., 1 (Box 25)
    - Claypoole, James, 1720-1796., 2 (Box 25)
    - Clearfield, Louise, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Clemens, Paul, 1911-?., 1 (Box 25)
    - Close, Chuck, 1940-., 4 (Box 25)
    - Clover, Susan, 1943-., 1 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Cod-Coo., 21 (Box 25)
    - Codman, Charles, 1800-1842., 2 (Box 25)
    - Cohen, George, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Cohoon, Hannah, 19th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Coit, Caroline,19th c?., 1 (Box 25)
    - Cole, Alphaeus P., 1876-1988., 3 (Box 25)
    - Colescott, Robert, 1925-., 3 (Box 25)
    - Collins, Alfred, 1855-1903., 2 (Box 25)
    - Cone, Davis, 20th c., 2 (Box 25)
    - Condo, George, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Conger, William, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Connah, Whit, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Conrow, Wilford, 19th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Constant, George, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Cooper, Peter, 18th c., 1 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Cor-Coz., 17 (Box 25)
    - Corcos, Lucille, 1908-1973., 4 (Box 25)
    - Corne, Michel F., 1752-1845., 2 (Box 25)
    - Cornelius, Aleta, 1922-., 1 (Box 25)
    - Cottingham, Robert, 1935-., 3 (Box 25)
    - Cotton, William, 1880-?., 1 (Box 25)
    - Cowles, Eussell, 1887-?., 1 (Box 25)
    - Cox, Gardner, 1906-?., 2 (Box 25)
    - Cox, John Rogers, 20th c., 2 (Box 25)
    - Cozzens, Frederick S., 1856-1928., 1 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Cr., 12 (Box 25)
    - Crampton, Rollin, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Crane, Bruce, 1857-1937., 2 (Box 25)
    - Crawford, Ralston, 1906-., 2 (Box 25)
    - Crecelius, Ludwig, 19th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Crisp, Arthur, 19th c?., 1 (Box 25)
    - Criss, Francis, 1901-?., 2 (Box 25)
    - Crocker, J. Denison, 1823-?., 1 (Box 25)
    - Crockwell, Douglas, 20th c., 1 (Box 25)
    - Crown, Keith, 1918-?., 1 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Cu., 6 (Box 25)
    - Culverhouse, Johann M, 1859-1891., 2 (Box 25)
    - Cummings, e e, 1894-1962., 2 (Box 25)
    - Curran, Charles C., 1861-1942., 2 (Box 25)
  - Individual Artists (Box 25–26)
    - Cadmus, Paul, 1904-., 13 (Box 26)
    - Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976., 7 (Box 26)
    - Carles, Arthur B., 1882-1952., 5 (Box 26)
    - Carlsen, Emil, 1853-1932., 3 (Box 26)
    - Carroll, John, 1892-1959., 3 (Box 26)
    - Carroll, Leon, 1887-1937., 4 (Box 26–27)
    - Cassatt, Mary, 1844-1926., total of 102 photographs. (Box 27)
      - Location Unknown, 23 (Box 27)
      - Private Collection, 7 (Box 27)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-C, 20 (Box 27)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: D-Z, 13 (Box 27)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: D-Z, continued., 18 (Box 27)
      - Washington D.C., 21 (Box 27)
    - Catlin, George, 1796-1872., total of 20 photographs. (Box 27–28)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 9 (Box 28)
      - Washington D.C., 11 (Box 28)
    - Cavallon, Giorgio, 1904-., 5 (Box 28)
    - Chambers, Thomas, c. 1808-1866., 6 (Box 28)
    - Chase, William Merritt, 1849-1916., total of 56 photographs. (Box 28)
      - Location Unknown, 12 (Box 28)
      - Private Collection, 4 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-L, 10 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: N, 11 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: P-Z, 19 (Box 28)
    - Church, Frederick Edwin, 1826-1900., total of 54 photographs. (Box 28–29)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 9 (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, continued., 24 (Box 29)
      - Hartford, 11 (Box 29)
      - New York, 10 (Box 29)
    - Clonney, James Goodwyn, 1812-1867., 10 (Box 29)
    - Cole, Thomas, 1801-1848., total of 97 photographs. (Box 29–30)
      - Location Unknown, 5 (Box 30)
      - Private Collection, 3 (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-K, 6 (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-K, continued., 8 (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: L-Z, 13 (Box 30)
      - Detroit, 8 (Box 30)
      - Hartford, 12 (Box 30)
      - New York, 22 (Box 30)
      - Utica, 8 (Box 30)
      - Washington D.C., 12 (Box 30)
    - Colman, Samuel, 1832-1920., 5 (Box 31)
    - Congdon, William, 1912-., 3 (Box 31)
    - Copley, John Singleton, 1738-1815., total of 209 photographs. (Box 31)
      - Drawings, 23 (Box 31)
      - Location Unknown, 13 (Box 31)
      - Private Collection, 10 (Box 31)
      - Private Collection, continued., 50 (Box 31)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-E, 14 (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: F-M, 10 (Box 32)